y'all have heard me say it before and
I'm going to say it again dumbbells are
my favorite piece of workout equipment
It's just tough to beat the versatility
in my opinion I mean you can simply do
it all with a good old-fashioned pair of
dumbbells however
they do take up a ton of space in your
home gym so thankfully we have
adjustable dumbbells such as the Bowflex
select Tech 552 adjustable dumbbells
I've been able to get some solid usage
out of these bad boys in the past so why
don't we break everything down for y'all
what's up everybody it's Jake back in
the barbing garage gym with another
review ready to go for y'all today this
time I've got the Bowflex select Tech
552 adjustable dumbbells in this video
I'm going to tell you everything you
need to know about this product from the
price and the features the pros and the
cons you may experience and of course
who should or maybe should not buy these
but before I get going with all of that
I gotta let you know we've reviewed a
lot of adjustable dumbbells on
barbin.com and if you want to browse our
best list just go and search bar Bend
best adjustable dumbbells you can find
out for yourself which one takes home
that number one spot
foreign
okay so what do I like about these
adjustable dumbbells well first and
foremost they don't require a whole lot
of space so you can easily stash these
in your closet or simply in the corner
of your room and it's going to be just
fine they go up to 52 and a half pounds
which is perfect for a lot of people who
work out at home it's really easy to
adjust the weight as well all you have
to do is simply twist the knobs on
either side of these adjustable
dumbbells it's gonna be really nice for
you also like how you have some two and
a half pound increments to work with
that kind of goes a long way with some
dumbbells and lastly is the price you
know considering the work you're going
to be able to put in with these
dumbbells and compared to some other
ones that are on the market this is a
really good deal that you're working
with right here
okay so let's talk about the cons now
with these Bowflex select Tech 552
adjustable dumbbells so first and
foremost talk about the weight they max
out at 52 and a half pounds that might
be plenty for a lot of you watching but
there's also a lot of you watching that
are gonna need more than that if that's
the case you're gonna have to keep
looking now let's also talk about the
materials here so let's talk about the
handle first so instead of a knurling
pattern you have a rubber grip in the
middle now I personally haven't had any
issues with that but it definitely has a
way different feeling overall compared
to you know your classic dumbbells that
you may use at a gym
other than the handle being made of
steel and a couple other of the
mechanisms in here that are made of
steel pretty much everything is made of
plastic now I don't want you to think
they're just going to break as soon as
you drop them but you do run that risk
if you were to you know put these back
in the Cradle too rough or you know
you're maxing out and say you drop them
on accident
you do run the risk of that plastic
cracking on you so you definitely want
to be careful now
another thing here is that they can get
stuck on you when you know with the
adjustment mechanism and also just
pulling them out of the Cradle so that
could be an issue at times trust me I've
experienced it myself so definitely keep
that in mind as well and lastly
regardless of the weight you're using
they're the same length no matter what
even five pounds 52 and a half pounds
the same length so that could be a
little bit tricky for some movement say
bicep curls for example so it's gonna be
something you're gonna have to get used
to
[Music]
okay so let's talk about pricing now the
Bowflex selectec 552 adjustable
dumbbells available for right around 470
bucks now that's including your shipping
and your taxes you know comparing this
to a bunch of the other competitors out
there it's a really solid deal I mean
these are about half the price of some
other ones that I've used and even
reviewed for y'all so you know
considering that it don't take up a
whole lot of space that they're going to
replace 15 individual dumbbells and you
know 52 and a half pounds is going to be
great for a lot of people you can get a
lot of work in with these I think it's a
really solid deal specifically for
anybody who's a tight on space and B
doesn't need more than 52 and a half
pounds foreign
okay so let's talk about the build and
some of the features now with these
Bowflex adjustable dumbbells let's talk
about the handles first and foremost
it's an ergonomically shaped handle so
it is thicker in the middle these are
pretty thick though I don't know the
exact diameter it's not listed online
but you know comparing them to some
other dumbbells out there seem to be
about 35 millimeters or so now that's
pretty thick it's going to fill up your
palm really nice I actually really like
that so people might not but a personal
preference right there and once again
you do not have a knurling pattern at
all you have you know a rubber grip
right here it's okay it really doesn't
you know hinder me in any way but it
could for some people might get a little
bit slippery if you get some really
sweaty hands while you're working out
now other than the steel handle pretty
much everything else right here is in
fact made of plastic now definitely
don't want to drop these a whole lot you
know a couple times here and there they
might be fine but you do run the risk of
cracking them so you definitely want to
be extra careful with these right here
and in terms of adjusting the weight
it's super simple all you have to do is
Twist either end you're going to fly
right through all the settings right
here I just went from 10 to 52 and a
half all the way back to 10. so it's
really cool you can just keep turning it
you'll have to go one way or the other
so that's really cool foreign
okay so let's go and do a quick walk
around with these dumbbells really fast
let's talk about the handle first you
know ignore the fact these don't look as
pretty as some other equipment I've
reviewed as I mentioned I've had these
for a good amount of time I wasn't lying
about that these have gotten a lot of
solid usage in now this handle right
here it is ergonomically shaped so it's
thicker in the middle than it is on the
ends you also have this rubber grip
right here I personally don't have a
problem with that and my hands tend to
sweat a lot when I'm working out so it
could be fine for a lot of you but it
still doesn't feel like a normal
dumbbell does so I understand if you
aren't too crazy about that there is a
lot of plastic used right here to build
these minus that handle and some of the
mechanisms on the inside for adjusting
so definitely want to be careful you
know you definitely run the risk of
these cracking whether that be the
Cradle or the actual plates right here
if you drop them if you set them in the
Cradle too hard
so you definitely just want to be super
careful with these and it's actually a
pretty simple process to adjust the
weight just so long as it's not getting
stuck on you I think the age of these is
having an impact on that but they still
do get stuck a lot when I go to adjust
the weight as well as just pulling the
dumbbells out of the Cradle so I'm going
to show you how to adjust them up close
have them on five pounds right now
let's go and adjust that to 10 as you
can see that was really easy right now
you pull it out you'll see just how big
these really are they take up a good
amount of space and once again it's
going to be this length no matter what
weight you're using it's because of just
the style of dumbbell and like how they
just designed everything so definitely
keep that in mind so that was 10 pounds
it's going up it
put it on 20.
went the wrong way on this side go and
pull this out now as you can see it's
still the same length and if I had it on
the five pounds there'd be no plates on
either side and it's still gonna be the
same length so it's just one of those
things you have to work around and maybe
adjust the way you do some of your
exercises when you're working out
[Music]
all right so who should purchase the
Bowflex select Tech 552 adjustable
dumbbells well if you're tight on space
I think you're going to love how compact
these are they're going to replace 15
individual dumbbells that's gonna be
really nice make the most of your
available space if you don't need more
than 52 and a half pounds this is a
really good option for you to consider
you're gonna get some really solid usage
out of these bad boys trust me and
lastly the price if you're on a tight
budget I think you're gonna love the
price that these are featured at I mean
like I said they're about half of what
some other companies are charging for
their adjustable dumbbells
[Music]
okay so what about the people who might
not want to purchase these adjustable
dumbbells well if you do in fact need
more than 52 and a half pounds you'll
want to keep looking there are some
companies that do in fact offer
adjustable dumbbells that are heavier
than 52 and a half pounds because
there's a good amount of plastic used
here I mean for the most part all of
this is plastic you definitely you know
run the risk of some durability issues
so you definitely don't want to drop
them if you're somebody who you know is
worried about that I'd suggest you know
sourcing some other options and lastly
regardless of what weight you're using
these are going to be the exact same
length that's because of the design and
the smallest plate on either side is on
the end so I have it on five pounds
right now I'm gonna pick it up and as
you can see it got a little suck right
there but yeah I mean this is pretty
lengthy and that could definitely be an
issue for some people during their
workouts
well I love hanging out with y'all but
I'm afraid that's all I got for you
today on the Bowflex select Tech 552
adjustable dumbbells these are a really
solid value considering they're pretty
affordable take up minimal space they're
going to replace 15 individual dumbbells
you can get a lot of good work in with
these but remember they only max out at
52 and a half pounds and there's a lot
of plastic use here so this is going to
be more tailored for anybody who does
not need more weight than is offered as
well as anybody who's going to be really
careful with them thanks for hanging out
with me y'all I hope this video was
really helpful and I was able to answer
any questions you may have about these
adjustable dumbbells as always stay
posted for my next review but for now
why don't you head over to barbin.com
and you can read more about this product
just search bar Bend Bowflex select Tech
552 adjustable dumbbell review you can
read everything I talked about here
today I'll see y'all next time